这里是重庆市二零二一年初中学业水平暨高中招生考试
英语听力测试部分。
听力测试正式开始，请考生
开始答题。
第一节，听一遍。
根据你所听到的句子，从
三个选项中选出最恰当的答语，并把答题卡上对。
并题目的答案标号涂黑。
每小题你将有七秒钟的时间读题和答题。
第二节，听一遍。
根据你所听到的对话和问题，从
三个选项中选出正确答案，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
每小题你将有八秒钟的时间读。
第三节：听两遍。
根据你所听到的长对话，从
三个选项中选出正确答案，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标。
号涂黑。
听长对话前，你将有十秒钟的时间阅读各个小题。
听完后，你将有十秒钟的时间答题。
听第一段材料，回答第十。
小题。
What have you grown in your field?
We have grown some carrots and potatoes.
Good choice. By the way, who teaches you the life skill course?
Miss Green. She's really nice.
Hi Linda, why are you in such a hurry?
I'm going to get some tomatoes from our vegetable field.
That's wonderful. Can I go with you?
Of course, Steve.
What have you grown in your field?
We have grown some carrots and potatoes.
Good choice. By the way, who teaches you the life skill course?
Miss Green. She's really nice.
听第二段材料，回答第十五和十六小题
Any plans for this evening, Susan?
Yes, I want to watch a
Are there any good movies on right now?
Let me see.
What about something exciting, like action movies?
Oh no, I don't like action movies at all.
They are boring.
What about Hi Mom?
It is popular these days.
Sounds great. Would you like to go with me?
Ok, let's meet at 7.30 in the evening.
See you then.
See you. Any plans for this evening,
Yes, I want to watch a movie.
Are there any good movies on right now?
Let me see.
What about something exciting, like action movies?
Oh no, I don't like action movies at all.
They are boring.
What about Hi Mom?
It is popular these days.
Sounds great. Would you like to go with me?
Ok, let's meet at 7.30 in the evening.
See you then.
you. 4. Listen Listen twice.
第四节，听两遍。
根据你所听到的短文内容，从
三个选项中选出正确答案，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
听短文前，你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读各个小题。
听完后，你将有二十秒钟的时间。
答题。
Listen twice. Listen twice.
Welcome to our health program.
I'm Dr. Smith.
Today we are going to talk about how to protect our eyes.
Nowadays many of us get eye problems.
That's because we don't use our eyes properly.
We can't watch the screen of a TV, a computer or a phone for a long time.
Every 20 minutes we should stop to look at something far away.
And we should wear sunglasses when out in the We'd better not read in the sun.
It's harmful to our eyes.
Another important thing is to get an eye examination every two years.
If the doctors notice our problems earlier, it'll be easier for them to correct the
problems. Eyes are important.
Hope all of us can keep our eyes healthy.
Thanks for listening to today's program.
See you next time.
Welcome to our health program.
I'm Dr. Smith.
Today we are going to talk about how to protect our eyes.
Nowadays many of us get eye problems.
That's because we don't use our eyes properly.
We can't watch the screen of a TV, a computer or a phone for a long time.
Every 20 minutes we should stop to look at something far away.
And we should wear sunglasses when out in the sun.
We'd better not read in the sun.
It's harmful to our eyes.
Another important thing is to get an eye examination every two years.
If the doctors notice our problems earlier, it'll be easier for them to correct the
problems. Eyes are important.
Hope all of us can keep our eyes healthy.
Thanks for listening to today's program.
See you next time.
Hope all us can keep healthy.
Thanks
听力测试完毕，请考生们继续完成其他。
试题。